人們說歷史由勝利者書寫
They say that history is written by the victors.
如今的歷史則由保護傘公司書寫
This then, is the history of the Umbrella Corporation.
科學運動家、教授詹姆斯·馬庫斯組建了該公司
Formed by crusading scientist, Professor James Marcus.
馬庫斯小女兒愛麗莎患有早衰癥
Marcus had a young daughter, Alicia, afflicted with progeria,
一種漸進性致命的消耗性疾病
a progressive, fatal, wasting disease.
能導致過早老化
Progeria caused premature aging.
當她25歲時 已經是90歲的體質
By the time she was 25, Alicia would have the body of a 90 year old.
馬庫斯竭盡全力解救她
Marcus was driven to save her.
但希望渺茫
But the odds seemed impossible.
儘管拚命發明解藥
And even as he worked desperately to create a cure,
這位父親會錄下女兒的聲音
the young girl's father would record his daughter,
記錄她的外貌 用來延續後代
her voice, her likeness, saving her for posterity.
接著迎來了大突破 馬庫斯發現了T病毒
But then a breakthrough came. Marcus discovered the T-Virus.
一經注射 它將探測並修復體內的壞細胞
Once injected, it would detect and repair damaged cells within the body.
那是個奇跡
It was a miracle.
愛麗莎被救活
The life of Alicia Marcus was saved.
T病毒有無數用途 可治療上千種疾病
The T-Virus had a myriad of applications, treating a thousand different diseases.
那夜 似乎沒有感染、疾病和衰老的
Overnight, it seemed a new era was dawning.
新世紀將要來臨
A world without the fear of infection, sickness or decay.
但事實並非如此
But it was not to be.
T病毒的確有副作用 但難以預測
For the T-Virus had certain, unforeseen side effects.
先生們 快過來
Sir, sir, over here!
沒有呼吸了
He's not breathing.
第一批不死者誕生
The first of the undead was born.
這件事被迅速掩蓋
The incident was quickly covered up.
結果 馬庫斯與他的商業夥伴亞歷山大·艾薩克博士
In the aftermath, James Marcus argued furiously with his business partner,
發生激勵爭吵
Dr. Alexander Isaacs.
不管花費多少 計劃必須終止
I don't care how much it costs. We have to close the program down.
- 詹姆斯 我們會破產 - 我意已決
- James, we're gonna be ruined. - My mind is made up.
真遺憾
Pity.
回去睡覺 愛麗莎  我只是跟你父親談談
Off to bed, Alicia. Your father and I are just talking.
回去吧
Go on.
艾薩克博士成為死去夥伴的女兒的監護人
Dr. Isaacs became the guardian of his dead partner's child.
也擁有了屬於她的股權
And her half of the company.
以崇高理想開始的公司
The corporation that had begun with such lofty ideals,
已因貪婪和霸權而墮落
had been seduced completely by greed, and power.
為協助管理保護傘公司的巨額利益
To help him control the now vast interests of the Umbrella Corporation,
艾薩克博士創造了強大的人工智能
Dr. Isaacs created a powerful artificial intelligence.
艾薩克用愛麗莎的肖像作為計算機的界面
Isaacs used the likeness of Alicia Marcus for the computer's interface.
命名為紅後
Isaacs called the computer The Red Queen.
十年前 浣熊市暴發疫情
Then, 10 years ago in Raccoon City, there was an outbreak.
T病毒從名為「蜂窩」的地下實驗室洩漏
The T-virus escaped from an underground laboratory called The Hive.
美國政府試圖引爆炸彈控制其蔓延
The American government attempted to contain the outbreak by detonating a bomb.
毀滅了浣熊市
It devastated Raccoon City.
但阻擋不了風媒傳染
But it couldn't stop the airborne infection.
病毒於數日內傳遍全球
The viral outbreak spread across the world within days.
人類屈服了
Humankind was brought to its knees.
最終 人類最後的、也是最美好的希望
Finally, the last and best hope of humanity,
聚集在華盛頓 進行最後一搏
gathered and took a last stand in Washington DC.
但沒人料到我們正踏入的
But we didn't realize that what we had walked into...
是個陷阱 我叫愛麗絲 這是我的故事
Was a trap. My name is Alice. And this is my story.
我講完了
The end of my story.
生化危機：終章
快點啊
Come on!
有人嗎
Hello?
有人活著嗎
Is there anyone alive in here?
有人嗎
Hello?
- 你是來這幸災樂禍的嗎 - 我的衛星顯示
- You come here to gloat? - My satellites show
地表剩餘4472人
there are 4,472 humans remaining on the surface of the Earth.
48小時內 他們將滅絕
They will cease to exist in under 48 hours.
你想怎樣
What do you want from me?
是想讓我投降嗎
Want me to say that you've won?
- 你清除了人類 - 不 恰恰相反
- You've wiped out humanity. - No. Quite the opposite.
我要你阻止我
I want you to stop me.
注意後面
Behind you.
- 幹得好 - 我不相信你
- Nicely done. - I don't trust you.
鑒於歷史 我早已料到你不答應
Given our history, I'd be surpirised if you did.
但如果你不干預 人類會被全部消滅
But unless you intervene, the slaughter will be complete.
- 將無人倖存 - 我要怎麼幫忙
- There will be no survivors. - How can I possibly help them?
保護傘開發出風媒的抗毒素
Umbrella developed an airborne antivirus.
釋放後會消滅T病毒和被接觸感染的一切
If released, it would destroy the T-Virus and anything it has infected on contact.
- 管用嗎 - 保證
- All this could end? - Precisely.
- 抗毒素在哪裏 - 浣熊市地下的蜂窩裏
- Where is this antivirus? - Beneath the streets of Raccoon City, in the Hive.
- 你為什麼要幫我 - 我的程序編製不允許我損害
- Why would you help me? - My programming will not allow me to harm
保護傘公司的利益 但你沒有這種限制
the Umbrella Corporation. But you are bound by no such constraints.
你要背叛保護傘 還有你的創造者？ 為什麼？
You'd turn against Umbrella? Against the people who created you? Why?
在48小時內抵達浣熊市 進入蜂窩
Get to Raccoon City in 48 hours. Make it to the Hive.
你將找到答案
And then you'll have your answer.
我一個字也不相信
I have no reason to believe a word you say.
是真的 我能提供你非常想要的東西
True. But I can offer you something you want very much.
- 那是什麼 - 復仇 威斯克
- What is that? - Revenge. Wesker.
原傘公司研究員
他引你去華盛頓 他要還給你你的力量
He led you all here to Washington. He pretended to give you your powers back.
接著 他背叛了你
And then, he betrayed you.
他在哪裏
Where is he?
他剛到蜂窩 我將重制你的手錶
He just landed at the Hive. I'm resetting your watch.
時間緊迫
The clock is ticking.
愛麗絲
Alice.
十年前在蜂窩 我們都失敗了
Ten years ago in the Hive, we both failed.
造成這個狀況
We let this happen.
不要重蹈覆轍
Make it right.
你就這點本事？
Is that all you got?
未授權用戶
愛麗絲
Alice.
十年前在蜂窩 將無人倖存
10 years ago in the Hive... There will be no survivors...
這是什麼地方
What is this place?
我在哪裏 回答我
Where am I? Answer me!
- 你怎麼了？誰幹的？ - 閉嘴 安靜
- What's wrong with you? Who did this? - Be quiet. Quiet!
我跟你說過…
I told you...
安靜
Silence.
你還是醒了
So you're awake at last.
- 我殺死了你 - 這不還活著嗎
- I killed you. - Yet here I am.
克隆體…
A clone...
- 我殺死了你的克隆體 - 我最棘手的便是
- I killed your clone. - You've been most troublesome to me.
你和你的姐妹
You and your sisters.
現在你們在我手上
And now I have you.
清洗行動本應在一年前結束
The cleansing operation should've finished over a year ago,
但你們拖了後腿
but you slowed us down.
這樣以至於我不得不親自控制
So much so, that I was obliged to take command myself.
你可以結束這一切
You  could end all of this.
為什麼不呢
Why don't you?
有趣
Interesting.
有人跟你說了 是吧
Someone told you something, didn't they?
哦 你很快就會告訴我了
Oh, well, you'll be begging to tell me soon enough.
她不可輕信
She's an unbeliever.
我們怎麼處置不輕信者
What do we do with unbelievers?
趕走她
Cast her out!
趕走她 趕走她
Cast her out! Cast her out!
- 拜託 - 趕走她
- Come on! - Cast her out!
趕走她
Cast her out!
上帝使洪水氾濫 清洗地球
God created a flood to cleanse the Earth.
降雨四十晝夜 我們的方法要更長時間
40 days and 40 nights of rain. Our method is taking a little longer,
但殊途同歸
but the result will be the same.
正義和純粹將繼承這個世界
A world ready for the righteous and the pure to inherit.
再過半天多時間 我們就到浣熊市了
We reach Raccoon City in just over 12 hours.
我想你跑不了那麼長時間
I doubt even you can run for that long.
我要知道你知道什麼事
I want to know what you know.
她要開口時告訴我
Tell me when she's ready to talk.
- 威斯克 - 艾薩克博士
- Wesker. - Dr. Isaacs.
看我在路邊發現了什麼
Look what I found on the roadside.
看來你在華盛頓的使命沒你想像的出色
It would appear your mission to Washington was less successful than you made out.
- 不可能 - 希望你沒漏下其他的小問題
- Impossible. - I hope you didn't leave any other loose ends.
還有一點 我覺得她知道風媒抗毒素的事
There's something else. I think she knows about the airborne antivirus.
- 怎麼可能 - 目前我也不清楚
- How can that be? - I don't know. Yet.
但是我們在前往浣熊市的路上逮住了她 她還有什麼理由要去那裏
But we caught her on the road to Raccoon City. Why else would she be headed there?
將蜂窩的安保級別調至最高
Raise the security level at the Hive to maximum.
任何人嚴禁出入 當她開口時我會告知你
No one in or out. I'll let you know when she talks.
上帝與你同在
God go with you.
- 聽見沒 安保級別調至最高 - 遵命
- You heard him. Security level to maximum. - As you wish.
上去看看怎麼回事
Get up there and check it out.
放開我
Release me!
- 打開它們 - 好的
- Open them. - Alright.
好的
Alright.
你不能用它 你逃不掉的
You can't use it. You can't escape!
幹掉她
Fire at her!
老天
Jesus!
長官
Sir.
她逃跑了
She's gone.
目標116千米 正在接近
Target is 72 miles and closing.
封鎖蜂窩 準備防禦
Lockdown the Hive. Prepare defensive measures.
讓浣熊市的線人保持警惕
And alert our operative in Raccoon City.
歡迎來到浣熊市
保護傘之家
歡迎回來
Welcome home.
風媒抗毒素…
Airborne antivirus...
48小時…
48 hours...
找到蜂窩
Make it to the Hive.
放開他 快放開他
Let him go! Let him go now!
放下槍 不然我們開槍了
Put it down or we'll shoot!
- 我說過 多克 我說過你錯了 - 冷靜點 克裏斯琴
- I told you, Doc! I told you you were wrong! - Calm down, Christian!
我們應該抓住機會殺了她
We should've killed her when we had the chance!
- 拜託在他殺死我們倆之前放下它 - 裏面是什麼
- Put it down, please. Before he tries to shoot the both of us. - What's in this?
- 純腎上腺素 我要你清醒 - 為什麼
- Pure adrenaline. I needed you awake. - Why?
有東西進來 從你來的那個方向 是個大傢伙
There's something coming. In the same direction you came in. Something big.
放開他 放下槍 現在
Let him go! Put it down, now!
愛麗絲
Alice.
保護傘在阿卡迪亞抓了我
Umbrella captured me at the Arcadia.
我們朝叫做蜂窩的地方行進
We were headed somewhere called the Hive.
鬆綁 殺掉飛行員 在這裏墜毀
Got loose, killed the pilot. Crashed here.
多克他們把我從廢墟拖出來
Doc and the others pulled me from the crash.
- 我欠他們一條命 - 多克
- I owe them my life. - Doc!
從那裏往東
There, to the east.
它還是往我們這裏來
It's still headed our way.
你知道是什麼東西嗎
You know what it is?
保護傘 艾薩克博士
Umbrella. Doctor Isaacs.
我以為你殺了他
I thought that you killed him.
我也以為是
I thought so, too.
他有一支喪屍軍隊 幾個鐘頭就能來這
He has an army of undead with him. He'll be here within hours.
- 我們怎麼辦 - 他媽的為什麼要問她
- What do we do? - Why the hell are we asking her?
她是個陌生人 我們應…
She's a stranger. We should have...
- 嗨 -別碰我 多克
- Hey, hey! - Don't you touch me, Doc!
- 放下槍 克裏斯琴 - 你放下槍
- Put it down! Christian! - You put it down!
看著我 別以為你覺得你應該作主 就能控制一切
Look at me. Just cause you think you should be in charge, doesn't make it so.
聽著 多克 你們所有人都會後悔的
You listen to me, Doc. You're gonna regret it. All of you!
所有人
All of you!
我必須去蜂窩了
I have to get to the Hive.
- 你得把人們救出來 - 我們有孩子、傷員、老人
- You have to get these people out of here. - We have children. Injured. The elderly.
- 可在大路上能有什麼生還機會 - 總比在這好
- Now what chance do they have on the open road? - Better than they have here.
- 這棟建築很安全 - 可能相對於喪屍是安全的
- This building is secure. - Maybe from the undead.
但是艾薩克博士有裝甲車、火箭筒和重武器
But Isaacs has armored vehicles. Rocket launchers, heavy ordinance.
他們會炸平這裏
They're gonna tear this place wide open.
多克
Doc!
她怎麼了
So what happened to her?
她引爆了我們邊界上的陷阱
She's set off one of the traps we had on perimeter.
並非故意為了喪屍
Not intended for the undead.
- 這是什麼 - 這間屋子的特產
- What is this? - Specialty of the house.
- 能讓你立即恢復狀態 - 我為什麼要相信你
- Have you in your feet in no time. - Why should I trust you?
給
Here.
多克 你需要出來一趟 人們很驚慌 克裏斯琴還幫倒忙
Doc, you need to get out there. People are scared and Christian's not helping.
- 要讓人們知道發生了什麼 - 好的
- We need to let people know what's happening. - Okay.
我得走了
I've got to go.
你朋友沒事的
Hey. Your friend's gonna be okay.
謝謝
Thank you.
- 你知道 我和他… - 我看出來了
- You know, he and I... - I noticed.
蜂窩裏有什麼
So what's in the Hive?
保護傘研發了解藥
Umbrella developed a cure.
風媒的抗毒素
An airborne antivirus.
它會摧毀任何與T病毒接觸的東西
It'll destroy anything infected with the T-Virus on contact.
- 誰告訴你的 你相信她嗎 - 紅後
- Who told you this? And you believed her? - The Red Queen.
如果我們能結束這一切呢
What if we could end all this?
你怎麼辦 你也被T病毒感染了
What about you? They infected you with the T-Virus.
你釋放了抗毒素 它會殺死你
You release this antivirus, it's going to kill you.
- 無所謂了 - 愛麗絲 我不是…
- Whatever it takes. - Alice, I'm not...
你知道我做的對
You know I'm right.
好吧
All right.
我們從這裏抵擋艾薩克
We stop Isaacs here.
拯救這些人
We save these people,
然後我們一起去
and then we go together.
沒有多少時間了
We don't have long.
我們開始吧
Let's get to it.
你還有什麼防禦措施
What else do you have for defense?
槍支不太多 有很多汽油
Not too many firearms, we have a big supply of gasoline.
給 你需要武器
Here. You need a weapon.
- 我們這就給她槍了 - 別擔心 克裏斯琴
- We're giving her a gun now? - Take it easy, Christian.
你可以使你的守衛失望 但我沒心思
You can let your guard down if you want, man. I don't intend to.
我進來的時候 有人在監視我
When I rode in here, someone was watching me.
他們完全可以喊我或鳴槍示意這個陷阱 卻沒有
They could've called out or fired a shot to warn me about the trap but they didn't.
- 你在說什麼 - 小心背後
- What are you saying? - Watch your back.
艾薩克博士 看來她從你掌心逃脫了
So Dr. Isaacs, it seems you let her slip through
不然還剩下什麼呢
your fingers. Or what remains of them.
別忘了你在跟誰講話 她在哪裏
Don't forget who you're talking to. Where is she?
浣熊市的一個定居點 線人說她準備開戰
A settlement in Raccoon City. Our informant reports that she's preparing for a fight.
好 我很快就到
Good. I'll be there in the hour.
主說：申冤在我
羅馬書12章19節
就這樣 繼續
That's it. Keep moving.
我們要把所有的汽油罐弄到這裏
We need all the gasoline cans over there.
- 克萊爾說這是你做的 - 對啦
- Claire said you built this. - That's right.
這以前是洗玻璃用的
This used to be a window washer.
- 我改裝了一下 - 你從哪裏學到這個的？
- I made a couple of changes. - Where did you learn to do that?
我父親開過拆車廠 我不喜歡
My father used to run a chop shop. I hated it.
地下拆車廠：拆裝被盜車輛以銷贓
- 天知道 我猜我還是用心了 - 好啊
- Who knew? I guess I was paying attention after all. - Good.
因為我要你把這東西改裝一下
Because I'm gonna need you to make a few more changes to this thing.
準備武器 高爆彈 殺無赦
Ready the weapons. High explosive rounds. No survivors.
他在這 他們來了 關大門
He's here. They're coming! Close the gates!
老天 是個軍隊
My God. It's an army.
- 我們怎麼辦 - 對啊
- What are we gonna do? - Yeah.
- 我們怎麼辦 - 殺光他們
- What are we gonna do? - We're gonna kill every last one of them.
準備射擊！
Prepare to fire!
準備！
Get ready!
點火！
Light it up!
射擊！
Fire!
- 該死 - 重裝
- Damn her! - Reload.
靠近 停下
Close it up. Full stop.
釋放誘餌
Release the bait.
- 有倖存者 開門 - 打開門
- There's a survivor. Open the gate. - Open the gate!
開火 別讓他們靠近她
Open fire! Keep them off her.
記號2
Marker 2!
開火
Fire!
克萊爾、多克 快離開 帶她進來
Claire, Doc, get out there. Bring her in.
快點
Come on!
等等
Wait.
她快到了
She's almost there.
開火
Fire.
該死 快關門
Damn you. Close the gate now!
克萊爾 他們突破了大門
Claire, they've breached the gate.
克萊爾！
Claire!
開火
Fire.
- 剃刀 行動！ - 是 聽見沒 推！
- Razor, now! - Right! You heard her. Push!
跑啊
Move!
離棄大門 回到障礙
Abandon the gate. Pull back to the barricades.
看樣子她黔驢技窮了 瞄準房頂
Looks like she's out of tricks. Target the roof.
所有人趴下！
Everybody get down!
現在！
Now!
- 愛麗絲 我們到障礙了 - 克萊爾 你拖住他們
- Alice! We're at the barricades. - Claire, you have to hold him there.
多克
Doc!
愛麗絲 我們堅持不了太久了
Alice! We can't hold on much longer.
現在離開那裏
Get out of there, now.
快撤退
Back up. Now!
所有槍炮準備
Bring all guns to bear.
開火
Fire.
她在哪？
Where is she?
她跑哪裏了
Where have she gone?
找到她
Find her.
關掉通風口 快
Close the vents! Now!
別開槍
Don't shoot!
你很矯健 卻不聰明
You're fast, but you're not too smart.
- 求你了別開槍 - 他在哪裏
- Don't shoot, please. - Where is he?
那裏
That way.
- 省點子彈吧 - 外面還有很多
- Save your ammo. - There's too many of these things still out here.
我來處理
I'll take care of it.
不
No.
- 行動 - 走！
- Move out. - Let's go!
享受這一程
Enjoy the ride.
- 各位 有個東西你們得看看 - 走
- Guys. There's something here you gotta see. - Go.
兩大波喪屍 直衝我們來
Two more armies of undead. Headed straight for us.
那裏 地平線上
There. On the horizon.
另一波在那裏
And a second over there.
我們沒有汽油了 我們沒法防禦了
We're out of gasoline. We're defenseless.
我必須去蜂窩 這是我們唯一的機會
I have to make it to the Hive. It's our only chance now.
- 我跟你去 - 算我一個 - 我也去
- I'll come with you. -Count me in. - Me, too.
還有我 我錯怪你了 見鬼
And me. I was wrong about you. Blow me.
我們知道你要踏入深淵
We know where you're going. Into the pit.
我們也要去
We want to come.
求你了
Please.
帶著裝置 你會用到的
Grab some gear. You're gonna need it.
- 那是什麼 - 蜂窩被炸開的一部分
- What is it? - The part of the Hive exposed by the blast.
我們從那進去
That's our way in.
- 走吧 - 我對付他
- Let's move! - I'll take point.
現在激活安全措施
Activate security measures now.
- 蜂窩安全完全激活並自動控制 - 不
- Hive security fully activated and automated. - No.
不要自動控制 我親自操作防禦
Disengage automation. I'll handle the defenses myself.
如果我保留控制權 防禦會更有效
Defenses will be more efficient if I retain control of them.
真的嗎 我怎麼記得上次她從這裏活著走出去了呢
Really? I seem to remember last time she was here she walked out alive.
我不打算犯同樣錯誤了
I don't intend to make that same mistake.
如你所願 蜂窩的防禦現在是你的了
As you wish. Hive defenses are now in your hands.
- 釋放地獄犬 - 地獄犬好戲上演
- Unleash the cerberus. - Cerberus on play.
你有家人嗎？ 在這一切之前？ 丈夫？ 家人？
Did you have someone? Before all this? Husband? Family?
- 不記得 - 怎麼可能？
- Can't remember. - How is that possible?
我剛醒來這一切就開始了
I woke up just when all of this was starting.
之前的記不起多少
Can't recall much before that.
有時我感覺這就是我的一生
Sometimes I feel like this has been my whole life.
逃亡 殺戮
Running. Killing.
- 是什麼？ - 有東西在跟蹤我們
- What is it? - Something's stalking us.
- 你確定？ - 我就是幹這個的
- Are you sure? - This is what I do.
跑
Run!
快跑
Run, fast!
來呀
Come on!
你們沒事吧
Is everyone okay?
這邊
This way!
就在我們身後
Right behind us!
它們為什麼停下
Why'd they stop?
- 也許害怕了 - 害怕什麼
- Maybe they're scared. - Scared of what?
下面的東西
Whatever's down there.
防爆門
封鎖蜂窩
Seal the Hive.
整體安全度 啟動關閉序列
我們走
Let's go!
愛麗絲
Alice!
- 你還好吧 - 還好
- You okay? - Yeah.
- 我子彈不多了 - 我在湖裏丟了槍
- My mag's half empty. - Lost my guns at the lake.
- 我只有一發了 - 再來一發我也沒了
- I only got one round left. - One spare mag and then I'm out.
沒槍沒子彈 我們為什麼還要下去
No guns, no ammo, what the hell are we gonna do down here?
- 愛麗絲 有光亮的是什麼 - 受損的一部分蜂窩
- Alice. What's with the lights? - There's a part of the Hive that's damaged.
- 電量不穩定 - 給 拿著
- Power's erratic. - Here. Take this.
喂 看著
Hey. Look.
你問過我為什麼背叛保護傘 我也許諾給你答案
You asked why I'd turn against Umbrella. And I promised you an answer.
T病毒釋放後不久
Soon after the T-Virus was released,
一個密件上傳至我的數據流
a secret file was uploaded to my data stream.
它是保護傘領導層的會議錄像
It was a recording of a meeting of the Umbrella High Command.
日期在病毒爆發的17個月前
Dated 17 months before the viral outbreak occured.
我們今天在這裏 不僅僅討論公司的未來
We're here today, not just to talk about the future of this company.
我們是來討論它的使命
We're here to talk about its destiny.
我們是來討論世界末日的
We're here to talk about the end of the world.
我們站在末日大決戰的邊緣 對於沒有解藥的疾病
We stand on the brink of Armageddon. Diseases for which we have no cure.
呼籲毀滅地球的原教旨基督徒宣稱
Fundamentalist states who call for our destruction.
我們無法控制核能
Nuclear powers over which we have no control.
即便我們航行於危險的水面
And even if we navigate these dangerous waters,
我們會面臨嚴峻的、甚至是不可避免的威脅
we face harder, even more inevitable threats.
全球變暖會在80年內融化極地冰川
Global warming will melt the polar ice caps within 80 years,
淹沒地表90%的居住地
flooding 90% of all habitable areas on Earth.
不等50年 人口盲目增長
Unchecked population growth will overtake
會趕上糧食產量 導致饑荒
food production in less than 50 years leading to famine.
還有戰爭 並非猜想 這是事實
And war. This is not conjecture. This is a fact.
無論如何 世界末日來臨
One way or another, our world is coming to an end.
問題是 我們也要同歸於盡嗎
The question is, will we end with it?
你什麼意思
What do you propose?
我打算我們來毀滅世界
I propose that we end the world...
用我們的方式
But on our terms.
精心安排的天啟
An orchestrated apocalypse.
可以清洗世界人口
One that would cleanse the world of its' population
但保留基礎設施和完整資源的
but leave its infrastracture and resources intact.
從前已經成功過一次了
It's been done once before. With great success.
少數天選者將度過暴風雨
The chosen few will ride out the storm,
不是在《創世紀》裏的方舟上 而是在
not in an ark as in the book of Genesis, but in safety.
安全的地下 結束時
Underground. And when it's over,
我們將登上淨化過的地球
We will emerge onto a cleansed Earth.
可以重新起源的地球 以我們的形象
One we can then reboot. In our image.
舊約《創世紀》： 神說 我們要照著我們的形像 按著我們的樣式造人
你如何試圖達到目的
And just how do you intend to achieve this?
救贖的方法已經在手邊了
The means of our salvation are already at hand.
我給了你T病毒
I give to you, the T-virus.
他們故意釋放了病毒
They released it deliberately.
當這份錄像上傳至我的數據流時
When this recording was uploaded to my data stream,
它在我的程序編製產生衝突
it created a conflict in my programming.
我被創造成為保護傘公司服務
I was created to serve the Umbrella Corporation,
而我也被編製成尊重人類生命
but I was also programmed to value human life.
艾薩克博士使病毒洩漏 謀害70多億人
Dr. Isaacs allowed the virus to escape. He murdered over 7 billion people.
我的編制不允許我傷害保護傘公司的員工
My programming will not allow me to harm an employee of the Umbrella Corporation.
我無法阻止艾薩克博士 而你可以
I am powerless to stop Dr. Isaacs, but you are not.
在37分鐘內 人類最後的定居點將不復存在
In 37 minutes, the last of the human settlements will fall.
將無人倖存
There will be no survivors.
你必須在這發生前釋放抗毒素
It is imperative that you release the antivirus before this occurs,
否則保護傘會勝利
or Umbrella will have won.
最後一件事 你面前有一隻耳機 戴好
There is one last thing. There is an earpiece in front of you. Put it in.
機密資料
我不能自己行動傷害保護傘公司的員工
I cannot, in my actions, harm an employee of the Umbrella Corporation.
但我可以告訴你保護傘在浣熊市有間諜
But I can tell you that Umbrella had an informant in Raccoon City.
這個人極有可能在你身旁
It is highly likely that this person is now here with you.
沒時間了 愛麗絲 你得抓緊了
Time is running out, Alice. You have to hurry.
很高興見到你 艾薩克博士
I'm glad to see you, Dr. Isaacs.
我們認為上次襲擊後沒有倖存者
We didn't think there'd be any survivors after that last attack.
- 水 - 是 當然 給艾薩克博士拿杯水
- Water. - Yes, of course. Get Dr. Isaacs some water.
- 那麼恢復浣熊市秩序 - 她不在那
- Then resume course for Raccoon City. - She's not there.
- 啥？ - 她去了深坑 我們得跟著
- What? - She went to the pit. We have to follow.
- 那可不是我的命令 我嚴格… - 我們得去深坑
- Those are not my orders. I have strict... - We have to go to the pit.
謝謝
Thank you.
- 這是哪裏 - 蜂窩的通風口
- What is this place? - It's an air intake for the Hive.
跟上
Come on!
別 當真？
No. Really?
暢通無礙
All clear!
快點 電力又啟動了
Hurry up! The power's coming back on!
- 克萊爾 - 快點 走
- Claire! - Hurry! Let's go!
快點
Come on.
Come on!
好了
Okay.
- 沒事吧 - 嗯
- You all right? - Yeah.
有人在監視我們
Someone's watching us.
反轉渦輪極性
Reverse polarity of the turbine.
鐵片反著轉了
The blades are going the other way.
我們得出去 鐵片在把空氣往外抽
We have to get out of here. The blades are sucking the air backwards!
快點
Come on!
不要！
No!
這邊
This way.
我們得趕緊了
We have to hurry.
等等
Wait!
我們走
Let's go.
剃刀
Razor?
沒事吧
Are you okay?
沒事
Yeah.
走
Let's go.
- 什麼東西 - 生物武器
- What the hell was that? - Bio-weapon.
- 這是個人 - 你看見克萊爾了沒 - 沒有
- This one's human. No. - Have you seen Claire?
- 剃刀呢 - 他沒挺過來
- Razor? - He didn't make it.
來
Come on.
得趕緊了
We have to hurry.
如果目標保持現有狀態
If the target continues on her present course,
- 她將在7分鐘內抵達這裏 - 喚醒他們
- she'll be here in under 7 minutes. - Wake them.
我的這個指令 僅用於最緊急的時刻
My instructions are to do so, only in the greatest of emergencies.
現在喚醒他們
Wake them now!
警告 前方沒路
警告 危險 系統過載
警告 全部系統失敗
這是什麼地方
What is it?
得從這裏出去
We have to get out of here.
含示蹤劑爆破裝置
給 更多的武器
Here. More stopping power.
- 沒時間了 - 接著去哪裏
- Time's running out. - Where to next?
- 我們腳下的蜂窩最後一關 - 我們怎麼下去？
- The final level of the Hive's below us. - How do we get down there?
就這樣
That's how.
- 他們在哪裏 - 低溫冷藏箱
- What are they? - Cryogenic storage.
可能上千個
Must be thousands of them.
保護傘領導層
The Umbrella High Command.
安全地渡過浩劫
Waiting out the apocalypse in safety.
權貴們的諾亞方舟
A Noah's Ark for the rich, and powerful.
你要幹什麼
What are you doing?
幫我個忙
Give me a hand.
完成了嗎
Is it done?
- 清洗工作完成了嗎 - 沒有
- The cleansing process is complete? - No.
- 那為什麼我醒了 - 我們有麻煩了
- Then why am I awake? - We had a problem.
- 我努力… - 省口氣
- I tried... - Save your breath.
我知道發生了什麼
I know exactly what's happening.
我們被背叛了
We've been betrayed.
就這樣
That's right!
在這
Over here!
來吧 就這樣
Come on. That's it!
跟著我
Follow me!
我們走
Let's go.
壞小子回來了
The bad seed returns.
或者說敗家女孩？ 不用站那兒 進來吧
Or is it the prodigal daughter? Well, don't just stand there. Come in.
畢竟你只有9分鐘來拯救世界
After all, you have only 9 minutes to save the world.
- 你是他本人嗎？ - 首先 我要你把武器放地上
- You're really him? - First things first, I'm gonna need you to place your weapons on the floor.
- 我憑什麼那樣做 - 這就是你想要的 是吧
- Why would I wanna do that? - This is what you're after, yes?
抗毒素 這一切的解藥
The Antivirus. The cure to all this.
啊 只有一小瓶
Well, there's only one vial.
我們在距地半英里密閉的地下室
We're half a mile underground in a sealed facility.
我扔在這裏 抗毒素哪也去不了
I drop it here, the antivirus goes nowhere,
你那渺茫的夢想會更早地破滅
and your hopeless dreams will die sooner rather than later.
乖女孩
Good girl.
- 你還是有武器 - 是的
- You're still armed. - Yes.
- 克萊爾會失望的 - 幾分鐘後
- Claire would be so disappointed. - In a few minutes,
克萊爾會死 和其他人 你知道的
Claire will be dead. Along with everybody else you know.
真會說話
That's sweet.
抱歉 親愛的
Sorry. My love.
卸下武器 炸藥 過來
Move away from the weapon. And the detonator. Come on.
她往公司的冷凍管裏放了炸藥
She placed explosives in the High Command cryo tubes.
- 謝謝 - 你做得很好 多克
- Thank you. - You've done well, Doc.
不用勞煩了 你成功不了的
Don't bother. You don't make it.
靠近碎冰錐 玻璃瓶 或者自來水筆
To the ice pick, the decanter or the fountain pen.
戰鬥預測軟體
目標中立 100%概率
還有 回答你的疑問 嗯
And, in answer to your question, yes...
且不說這些技術升級
apart from a few technological upgrades,
我是亞歷山大·羅蘭德·艾薩克博士
I'm Dr. Alexander Roland Isaacs.
- 本體 - 我在外面遇到的那個 他也是這麼想的
- The original. - The one I met out there, he thought exactly the same thing.
當然了 他們就是這麼設計的
Of course he did. That's how they're designed.
只要他們以為自己是本體
They always try harder and fight longer even to death
他們就總是奮力戰鬥至死
as long as they think they're the real thing.
無論如何 誰想知道他們只是可憐的擬態 抑或是沒用的復製品
After all, who wants to know they're just a poor imitation, or a worthless copy?
而把你帶給我
Which brings us to you.
- 不 - 別緊張
- No. - Oh come now.
你以為你就是愛麗絲本體
You thought you were the original.
多可愛啊
How delicious.
不 恐怕她才擁有那枚可有可無的獎章
No, I'm afraid she holds that dubious honor.
愛麗莎·馬庫斯 我的老夥伴詹姆斯的女兒
Alicia Marcus, daughter of my old partner, James.
保護傘公司的共有人 我身旁扎人的荊棘
Co-owner of the Umbrella Corporation and a painful thorn in my side.
- 也是我現在想移除的 - 沒時間了 愛麗絲
- What I now intend to remove. - Time, is running out, Alice.
- 你必須趕快殺掉他 - 也很高興見到你 愛麗莎
- You must kill him soon. - It's good to see you too, Alicia.
馬庫斯發明T病毒拯救她 效果卻沒能持久
Marcus created the T-Virus to save her but the effects didn't last.
多年我一直等她死掉
I've been waiting years for her to die.
我不是…
I'm not...
- 我不是復製品 - 真的嗎
- I'm not a clone. - Really?
你肯定想知道你為什麼不記得你的童年
You must've wondered why you remember nothing of your childhood.
你父親 你母親
Your father. Your mother.
- 那是失憶 - 不 你沒有記憶 因為你沒有生命
- Memory loss. - No. You have no memory because you had no life.
在十年前你被我們創造出來前 什麼也不是
Nothing before the mansion, when we created you, 10 years ago.
- 我知道我是誰 - 我不這麼認為
- I know who I am. - I don't think so.
你就是一個斷線的木偶
You're nothing more than a puppet whose strings were cut.
然後你徘徊著思考你是一個真實的女孩
And then you wandered around for a little while thinking you were a real girl.
可你不是 你只是一個智慧擬態
But you're not. You're just a clever imitation.
一個復製品
A facsimile.
而且更惱人
A rather troublesome one at that.
你撒謊
You're lying to me.
恐怕他沒有
I'm afraid he's not.
你是被用她的形象創造 和我一樣
You were created in her image, as was I.
我的相貌和聲音是基於愛麗莎的童年錄音
My likeness and voice were based on childhood recordings of Alicia Marcus,
由她父親合成
made by her father.
你的基因構造基於她的DNA
Your genetic structure is based on her DNA,
微調以避免折磨她的早衰疾病
tweaked to avoid the progeria aging disease that afflicted her.
我是她小的時候
I'm the child she was.
你是她將成為的女人
You are the woman she would've been.
不 你比我成為的更好
No. You are so much better than I ever could be.
我做了這一切
I let this happen.
我很虛弱
I was weak.
- 你不能那樣 - 時間用盡了 愛麗絲
- You cannot afford to be. - Time is running out, Alice.
啊 好感人啊
Ah, how touching.
壞女人三人組 因仇恨而聯合
The trinity of bitches, united in their hatred.
並非對你們有什麼好處
Not that it'll do you any good.
我每一步都在你們前面
I've been ahead of you every step of the way.
你們改變不了什麼 也救不了誰
You've changed nothing. You've saved no one.
世界還是會被清洗 勝利的還是保護傘公司
The world will still be cleansed and the Umbrella Corporation will triumph.
唯一的不同之處在於 我不再須要
The only difference is, I'll no longer have to
聽你自以為是的牢騷
listen to your self-righteous whining.
當你把那個文件傳至紅後的數據流時
When you uploaded that file to the Red Queen's data stream,
你背叛了公司
you turned against the Corporation.
當董事會都甦醒後 你將被取代
When the rest of the board awake, you'll be replaced.
- 我就可以佔有全部控制權 - 我仍擁有公司的一半
- And I will assume complete control. - I still own 50% of this company.
- 那你怎麼達到目的呢 - 你是公司的共有人
- And what do you intend to do with that? - You are co-owner of this corporation.
但是威斯克呢 威斯克仍是僱員
But Wesker? Wesker is still an employee.
我不用聽你命令 我忠誠於他
I don't have to take your orders. My loyalties are with him.
我知道
I know.
阿爾伯特·威斯克 你被開除了
Albert Wesker, you're fired.
保護傘公司員工 不要傷害
阿爾伯特·威斯克 237#員工 服務17年
平民 未保護
你怎麼知道是我
How did you know it was me?
你還活著
You're still alive.
求你了 我沒有選擇
Please. It wasn't like I had a choice.
- 他們讓我這樣做的 - 別擔心
- They made me do it. - Don't worry.
我不會殺你
I'm not gonna kill you.
- 克萊爾 是我 - 抱歉
- Claire, it's me. - Sorry.
- 求你了  - 吾愛
- Please. - My love.
不
No!
如果你繼續扣動扳機 保護傘的夢還會存在
If you keep this trigger depressed, you keep Umbrella's dreams alive.
我應該在華盛頓殺了你
I should have killed you in Washington.
是啊
Yeah.
他只需再逃避你幾分鐘
He only has to evade you for another few minutes.
人類最後的定居點就會覆滅
And the last remaining human outposts will fall.
我們需要一個截距路線 還有去地表最快的方式
We need an intercept path. And the fastest way to the surface.
已完成
Already done.
如果你釋放抗毒素 它會殺死所有感染T病毒的生物
If you release the Antivirus, it will kill all organisms infected with the T-Virus.
你知道那意味著什麼嗎
You know what that means, don't you?
- 我知道 - 愛麗絲 你不能
- I know. - Alice. You can't!
- 我沒有選擇 - 會有別的方法的
- I don't have a choice. - There has to be another way.
- 你知道沒有的 - 剩餘4分33秒 你要抓緊了
- You know there isn't. - 4:33 left. You have to hurry!
神經連接佔用
下載中…
救我
Help me.
你不需要救 威斯克
You don't need help, Wesker.
你快死了
You're dying.
繼續這樣就好
Just get on with it.
我是亞歷山大·羅蘭德·艾薩克博士
This is Dr. Alexander Roland Isaacs.
確認DNA掃瞄與聲紋識別
Confirm DNA scan and voice print identification.
- 身份確認 - 確認安全重寫4365
- Identity confirmed. - Confirm security override 4365.
確認完畢
Override confirmed.
把你自己脫機 所有功能由我控制
You will now take yourself offline and place all functions under my sole control.
遵命 正在關閉
As you wish. Shutting down now.
- 艾薩克博士 你和保護傘領導層 - 怎麼了
- Dr. Isaacs. You and the Umbrella High Command. - Yes?
你們將死在這裏
You're all going to die down here.
你的小朋友現在不能幫你了
Your little friend won't be able to help you now.
你逃不掉了
You can't run anymore.
我沒有逃跑
I wasn't running.
戰鬥預測軟體
MP5衝鋒鎗
8MM口徑 危險估計73%
0.45口徑 危險估計63%
武器系統解除
武器系統重啟
你就這點能耐？
Is that all you got?
因為如果是…
Because if it is...
我就會殺了你
I'm gonna have to kill you.
武器系統重新準備
你我玩了一個很長的遊戲
We've played a long game, you and I.
但現在結束了
But now it's over.
是
Yes.
是的
Yes, it is.
我創造了你
I made you.
是的
Yeah.
是個大錯誤
Big mistake.
克萊爾
Claire.
快去 還有時間
Go. While there's still time.
快去 我馬上跟上你
Go! I'll be right behind you.
時間到
Your time's up.
生命支持：危險
系統重啟中
系統故障
生命支持：0%
愛麗絲
Alice!
我把他們帶給你了
I brought them here! I brought them for you!
你他媽是誰
What the hell are you?
你呀 白癡
I'm you, you idiot.
不
No.
不可能
That's not possible.
真正的你
The real you.
不
No!
騙子！ 賤人！
Liar! Abomination!
穢人
Filthy,
克隆人
clone!
我才是我 他不是我
I'm me. He's not me.
你做到了 愛麗絲
You did it. Alice.
愛麗絲
Alice?
你做到了
You did it.
我為什麼還活著
Why am I still alive?
不知道
I don't know.
- 怎麼了 - 艾薩剋死後
- What happened? - When Isaacs died,
我就能重新上線阻止
I could bring myself back online and stop the attacks
對殘存人類定居地的進攻
on the remaining human settlements.
- 你救了他們 - 我為什麼還活著
- You saved them. - Why am I still alive?
抗毒素只摧毀你體內的T病毒
The Antivirus only destroyed the T-Virus within your body.
並不傷害健康細胞 你現在沒有感染了
It didn't harm the healthy cells. You are now free of infection.
我以為我會死 你和愛麗莎…
I thought I would die. You and Alicia...
- 撒了謊 - 我要確定你是否願意為他人犧牲
- You lied to me. - We had to know if you were willing to make the sacrifice,
這是保護傘公司裏沒人能做到的
to give up your life for others. This was something no one at Umbrella would've done.
愛麗莎·馬庫斯對你的判斷是對的 你比他們所有人更優秀
Alicia Marcus was right about you. You were better than all of them.
我曾是他們一員 我是保護傘創造的
I was one of them. I was created by Umbrella.
- 只是他們的工具 - 非也
- Just an instrument for them. - No.
你的變化大大超乎他們的預期
You became something more than they could ever have anticipated.
克隆體變得比其設定更像人類
The clone became more human than they ever could be.
你還有一步要走
And you have one more step to make.
什麼意思
What do you mean?
愛麗莎死前下載了她的記憶
Before she died, Alicia downloaded her memories,
提供給你
for you.
你從未有過的童年
The childhood you never had.
結合了她無法成為的那個女人
Combined with the woman she could never become.
T病毒在全球範圍內傳播
When the T-Virus spread across the Earth,
的速度和現代世界
it did so at the speed of the modern world.
噴氣機環行的速度相當
Carried by jetliners across the globe.
抗毒素是風媒傳播
The antivirus is airborne, spread by the winds.
到達地球每個角落需要幾年時間
It could take years for it to reach every corner of the Earth.
在那之前 我的工作不會結束
Until then, my work is not done.
我叫愛麗絲
My name is Alice.
曼哈頓西區
Bryan-T原創翻譯